Making it to a live hacking event is
already a big accomplishment, but my
guest today, Doomerhunter, not only
made it, but on all three events that he
attended, he achieved the top 10 finish.
So clearly he has some good methodology
to find crits on well hardened targets.
So we'll dive into this in this interview.
Hello, Victor.
How are you doing?
Can you please introduce yourself to
those viewers who don't know you yet?
Hi
Greg.
Well, first, thanks for having me.
It's so cool to be here
in Poland, in Krakow.
So I really enjoy it.
And thanks again for the tour yesterday.
Uh, yeah, I have quite some
of a specific background.
So basically I was not
into IT or into cyber.
I was into the pharmacological industry.
I have even a master's
degree in marketing.
Oh,
and, uh, it all switched
when, um, well, COVID hit.
Thanks.
And, uh, the job I should have in
North America and Canada was frozen.
So I was left with no other options.
And I was wondering to myself, Hey,
this big boaty thing seems a bit cool.
And I'm starting to make
a bit of money with it.
Could I make a living out of it?
And so, yeah, I decided to switch full
time into cyber, uh, offensive security,
and I got a small first pen testing
job at a local firm and met the guy
who become next, my future partner.
So we started our own business, uh, and
it was a pen test writing in company.
We did work together for three
years, brought the company to 1.
2 million euros, I think in turnover.
So really nice, uh, stuff had good
clients, did physical intrusion,
you know, physical pen testing.
It's awesome.
And, uh, on the side, we did
also bug bounty hunting because
as a small business, it was like
a cool, you know, um, front.
For you to say, okay, I'm performing
in real world on hardened targets.
And so that's how we started getting to,
you know, more competitive events, such
as the first AWC, the world cup that
we won with the French team in 2022.
And, uh, then we're all starting
to get into live hacking events.
I sold my shares of the company
to my partner this year.
So I'm back into full time
backhunting entrepreneurship.
That's pretty much what I do now.
Backhunting, I do a bit of AI on the side.
Uh, I do corporate talks also.
I'm invited to buy various companies
to give cybersecurity talks across
Europe.
That's pretty much it.
So how much time did it take for
you to get into cybersecurity from
the marketing or from the pharmacy
background or whatever it is?
That's why I lied a bit because,
you know, hacking was always the
things that I really wanted to do.
Yeah.
But I come from a family that
is into, you know, health.
They are mostly health practitioners.
And so I was more, you know,
inclined to do that as a real job.
And I didn't thought that it was
possible to get into cyber route.
And I thought that pentesting
was reserved to kind of elites,
you know, some few people.
And, um, so I did a bit
of hacking on this side.
I remember buying an old book called The
Art of Exploitation by John Erickson.
Yeah.
So it's a really old book, but
it still gives, you know, first
hands on approach with live CD.
It was so good at the time.
And so I practiced a bit during, well,
my university years, because I'd enjoy
doing some CTF on the side and so on.
And one day I had a friend, I was
maybe in my third year of uni.
And, uh, well, So she had a
loan, you know, to pay her
studies, her private school.
And well, sadly she started like, um,
buying stuff with the money from the loan.
So when September came, it was like
maybe June, she didn't have enough
money to pay for the next year.
So what do you do at that point when you
don't get much money, you want to help
your friend and don't have like an actual
job that makes that amount of money?
Well, you take a look at your skillsets.
Say, okay, I can do Hassam hacking.
Can I make money hacking?
Can I make legal money hacking?
What's the boundary?
Oh, Oh, that was a nice amount I can make.
So yeah, that's where I
landed my first create.
I think maybe you did some free K
on, uh, on Sam rush at the time.
And so he managed to go to cover
the costs and get back into it.
Then once again, I put it back into
the closet because I thought that
no, man, I'm in health carrier and
must not like ruin my future health
carrier by doing cybersecurity.
And then when I decided to really
make the switch, I had like a little
background, you know, couple of skills.
I know I could land some small
bounties, but I decided to really prep.
And when I took the decision, maybe
in, in May, 2020, I thought to myself,
okay, in September, I got my job.
So I got five months to get ready.
So I just took everything that, that, uh,
that I've already had and seek the, what I
would call quality content to really grow.
And so I first went to, uh, Louis.
Uh, we spent just a lab
because, uh, I really love the
approach, the hands on approach.
And he's one of the few guys
that really teaches you to, um,
actually deep dive into the source
code with like such an accessible
platform and high quality contents.
And also forces you to like,
understand how it's going, um, dissect
the CV, write the exploit code.
And I did like maybe five or six
badges that he had at the time.
Just to feel comfortable and, you
know, proud of myself and also set
up the certification on my LinkedIn
profile because I did not have
enough money to pay for the sets.
Yeah, that's a good way.
And then I did the thing, the full,
um, OASP juice shop, which is also,
I think a cool, um, you know, way to,
uh, go into like, So the real world
web applications, and then I got into
a small bug bounty platform in France,
which is called the yoga shop because
I didn't know any better at the time.
And so I'm making some, uh, some,
uh, some more active bug bounty.
And that allowed me to
transition, you know, correctly.
Now let's skip to, to the present
time after quitting the business,
what made you choose the life of
a full time bug bounty hunter?
Freedom.
Um,
once you're used to entrepreneurship,
you're used to producing
value for yourself directly.
Yeah.
And you're used to, well, valuing your
time and your efforts based on your
skill sets and how you bring added value
to the real world and to the companies.
And so once you have tasted that and
you feel confident enough to be alone
and stay by yourself, Honestly, it's
very hard to going back to classic job.
It's a one way ticket.
Exactly.
But it comes with a lot of costs
and a lot of responsibilities.
But, uh, I had like the money as
from my shares money from my personal
and professional bank accounts.
So I could finance, you know,
taking the risk of going back
to full time back hunting.
And also, let's be honest, uh, when
you start to perform a bit well on
back hunting, you do make a lot of
money and that allows you to open more
opportunities for yourself in the future.
So I was in a position where I had,
like, I think a good network flowing
the, my, my business here had a
bit of money in the bank could make
more with the, the big bounty parts.
And if you take all that by itself,
you got potential, then you got
to make this potential grow by the
building new things, keep building your
network and then keep making money.
Yeah.
So freedom and all the opportunities
that he brought was like.
Why I chose to,
to go along this path.
And also, if I understand correctly,
you do use Back Bounty as sort of the,
the way to grow your personal brand
and to, to also details of fuels,
the, the trainings that you give
and, and other things that you do.
So, you know, whenever you find a bag,
you're not only getting the bounty
from this bag directly, but also it
builds your personal brand, which,
you know, grows and grows forever.
You know?
Yeah.
Back in the days we used that, as of.
Kind of a front for our business
because as a small company, it was
really helpful, you know, to legitimize
yourself as, Hey, I was able to
find a bug on X, Y, Z big company.
It gives you like, you know, this
legitimacy and, uh, yeah, now
that it's all just by myself.
Yeah.
It's still a pretty way because I still
have like a small audience in France.
Um, and still show that you're
active, that you are indeed,
you know, a real hacker.
And I think it doesn't only like,
it's not only useful for the audience.
It's also used to comfort yourself.
Think, okay, I'm still a hacker.
You know, you still can force your, your
imposter syndrome or your ego, whatever
you want to, you, you want to call it.
And yes, it's also a way to, um, grow
a bit, um, the business part, because
when you, when you, for example,
when I give, um, cybersecurity talks
to companies and incorporate when
they are looking for speakers, they
are looking for what they consider.
You know, special people.
So often there will be like high level
athletes, you know, people from the
government, ex special forces and so on.
Yeah.
So you're here, you know,
and
so it, it helps you legitimate, you
know, your, your presence even through,
uh, I feel, I still feel uncomfortable
presenting myself, you know, in
front of people, but sometimes you
gotta do it just so that people, Hey.
He knows what he's talking about.
He
seems to know what he's talking about.
Yeah.
And it's a good way because a lot of
bug bounty you can speak publicly about.
So, you know, you can be
the best pen tester ever.
All your reports are confidential.
You cannot, you know, share
the defining from the pen test.
Even if you try to write it on the blog,
you have to redact the company name.
And, you know, it doesn't sound as well
when you find a good bug in bug bounty.
You know, Oh, I hacked Microsoft.
I had Google.
I had, it just sounds nice.
So when you hunt, what
is your hunting style?
What are your favorite bug classes?
That's a, that's honestly, it's even a,
what I consider weakness on myself that,
um, I remember, I think it's Justin from
critical thinking writer who, um, shared,
you know, his, um, his roadmap to, okay.
If I had one year to make a hundred
K in big bounty, how I would like,
you know, uh, invest my time.
during the different steps.
And I think one of those first
steps is getting to, um, comfortable
with access control bugs.
And when you get inside the, when
you, when you start your own business,
of course, you have to be someone
technical because you have to run the
business and technical part of it.
But then you start to, well, not
be that much hands on the technical
and offensive part of the set,
but more on quality management,
control, sales, marketing, and so on.
Everything on the side.
And I felt that I.
was kind of trapped inside that, you
know, comfort zone of being okay.
I'm pretty good with access control.
Yeah.
I think, uh, like I'm made a lot of
money with access controls because
it's easy to find it's repeatable.
And I love hunting for them because often
you get like very high impact full books.
And that's where we're where I stayed
for a long, long, long, long time.
So yeah, it's still my pee pee view.
I know that if I'm going on a new
program, first thing I'm going to
look is for access control bugs and
logic bugs, because I love that.
But then you start going
outside of this comfort zone.
I started to more into business logic
bugs, which are often, you know, more
hidden and less covered by modern
security tools, such as fast and dust.
When you know that, let's
say that you have an idle.
Okay.
You just increment a number.
Well, Once the issue is known, if
the developers take some time to
make unit testing, you can pretty
easily test the fact that, okay, if I
increment the number, then the result
of the test should be 403 forbidden.
Yeah, but then business logic bugs are
way more hidden because it's nested
inside like multi step workflows
and you cannot test all of the
possibilities of these workflows.
And so you still find these issues.
And I think it's all
still easy for me to find.
And it's also hard to come up with
a source code scanning rule to
detect business logic because there
is, there's no template for it.
It's just, you know, every single
code can have different logic,
different rules, different bugs in it.
So, um, so that's why I think these
bugs will be with us for, for longer
because, you know, obviously scanners
are getting better and better.
Frameworks are doing stuff like
automatically sanitizing the HTML.
So there's less XSS, but bugs like this,
they're not so easy to, to, To fix or the
tag that scale, I think are the ones that
will be with us for a long, long time.
Yeah, they will.
They will.
You cannot have a bug free,
like 20 step workflow.
It doesn't happen in real life.
And, and even there, we are
just scratching the surface.
Like, I don't know who made
the talk a couple of years ago
about, you know, everything
second order on the server side.
It was a really great talk and even if
you take like your five step workflow
of buying something and start to mix
up some parameters, add some parameters
that shouldn't be there, add some
ideas that are not matching, et cetera.
This is like only the
top levels of his bug.
And We often miss like
the second order bugs.
Like, I don't know if you start to
buy a TV and you put the insurance
of a phone on it, will it work?
But will it work if you like
create a custom insurance policy?
Like what happens deep down, you
know, further steps beyond that's
what's really scratches my mind.
But bug hunting, black box testing, we
don't have access to the source code.
And there is so many issues.
Hidden surface, not being covered in it.
And I think that's why
we should spend more time
fuzzing.
Yeah.
And also that's, you know,
we are never sure how many
different flows we didn't test.
Cause you know, I had a talk with, with
Jonathan in Edinburgh that, you know,
if you have, let's say Amazon, probably.
Shipping from one country has a
different code to handle the ship
shipping to another country who has
tested 200 countries in the world.
Probably not even him and Zeeshan
on Amazon in their six years.
So on many programs, we just have a
lot of code that we never touched,
but I think GripMe has
an interesting approach.
So GripMe is the one doing the notes for
the critical thinking about him podcast.
And he's also Rhino's
mentee, a very cool guy.
Yeah.
Very crazy story.
Uh, got into big bounty like
nine months ago, did the two
LH here at Vegas and Edinburgh.
Very cool guy.
He, by the way, he, he quit the work
this month to be a full time hunter.
And he has been very successful.
And when talking with him, he told
me that his own methodology was
trying to be more comprehensive.
building his checklist of what
could be the most impactful for
the company, and then really try
to assess all of these vectors.
And so he is indeed trying to be more
mythological and trying to build a
comprehensive way to like really test the
application, but through the lens, if I
understood correctly, of his perspective
of security model and what can impact it.
And I think that's a good way, you know,
to ensure that you have more coverage.
Yeah.
That's a good way.
And there's pretty much
There's no, no border to it.
There's no boundary that, because
there's just so much different
possibilities everywhere.
And that's the, uh, the overall answer
to, well, no new hunters like don't,
that don't want to hack on public
programs and each year there are
thousands of bugs, millions of dollars
being paid to different hunters.
I think once you are new to the
back hunting, you have something
that is called being naive.
And being naive allows you to explore
with a fresh view of the program.
When you start to hunt, you have
your spider sense, you know,
you got your instinct, you trust
your guts and say, okay, DSL
smells bad, I'm going to hack it.
And you're hacking it and you find issues.
That's, that's cool.
You're starting to get trapped
into your own routine, in your
own way of things, seeing things.
Whereas a newbie, Who is
very naive, doesn't know that
this is not going to work.
This is not going to work
because he's going to test it.
And by testing it, he's going to find
these issues in the spots that you,
your blind spot that you never tried.
That's why it's very cool to hunt
with like very new hunters because
they are going to test everything
that are going to find those little
tracks that you would have missed.
What are your, your top tips
to like uncover parts of the
application that nobody looked at?
Well, when I, um, start hunting on
the, on a program, The, you know, I, I
told you that my pet peeve was using,
uh, was working on access controls.
So when you want to uncover
more access controls, you've
got to unlock more feature.
And what I think to myself is even
when I think that I've covered
the whole application, I always
consider that I've missed something.
And by keeping And keeping
the grind on it, like trying
to test all the damn feature
everywhere, everywhere, everywhere.
That's how you start to understand
the, Oh, I miss that workflow.
workflow.
And then you start to understand like,
okay, there's way more hidden features
because nowadays you eyes are, you know,
very, um, like styled down, you know,
you don't see much buttons anymore.
So you have to really like
test all the flows all around.
Um, and so by.
It's a bit stupid, but I keep brute
forcing kind of the application.
You want to cover most of this.
Of course, the good old JavaScript
mining is very important.
And that's why tools like JS Weasel by
Steelman are very damn useful because,
um, it gives a really, like, really one
place to have everything stored, all
JS files, even that hidden JS file that
only is loaded on a, on a weird route.
You will have it.
And need.
Processes you, you know,
the potential path.
So that's a pretty, a pretty nice one.
And the thing, uh, the last
thing is being, um, logging.
So you have your burp
history or Cato history.
What I like to do is to try to, you
know, store that into a database.
When I, I'm strict enough with myself
to take the time to set up that.
Uh, and sometimes when you look into
your burp history or you look on to
some, on some parameters, you will
find like the hidden root or the hidden
params that you needed to unlock that
stuff.
How exactly do you look for this?
You have your database with
all the requests logged.
What do you do to find it?
Initially, what I used was the, um, with
logger plus plus, you have a feature
to export the request to Elasticsearch.
Yeah.
And using Elasticsearch, you can then
use the, um, the, uh, well, the full,
Elasticsearch, Logstash and Kibana.
And so Kibana acts as a kind of front end.
So we can type like SQL like requests,
you know, to find the specific stuff.
But the issue is that in Elasticsearch,
uh, to find like specific words
inside the requests or so, or the
response, it goes through a tokenizer.
And so you have a limit on the
length of the contents, for example,
a very large JS file of 5 or 10
megabytes, it will not really work
properly, except if you fine tune it.
But that's, for example, a cool way
to improve your coverage when you're
testing for access control or business
logic errors, because you're able
to find like very hidden parameters,
parameters that you missed, or
parameters that have a similar name,
but that you needed to craft like.
The Google write request for that newly
uncovered routes that you understood
that you found in the, in the GS.
Yeah.
So we just like have a reg X to look for
the, to find all the parameters in all the
JS files and history, something like this.
No, because I am not disciplined
enough to actually build that.
And that's why I love SteelMans just
result too, because it does that
for you and it removes you the heavy
lifting on that part.
Yeah.
It's really nice.
How about some back classes
you never look for, or do you
think are there, like, present?
Honestly, I suck at client side.
I'm very bad at it.
Because, you know, I used to do the
classical, you know, HTML injection
to popping in XSS and so on.
And, like, being in the live hacking
event and seeing the bugs shown on the
show and tales clearly shows me that
I'm years behind all those top hackers
doing, like, crazy post message stuff,
finding gadgets all over the source code.
They're all there.
Yeah.
They are found at each event and very
impactful bugs are found with that.
I just never took the time to actually,
well, do all the CTF, do all the training.
And it's, it's kind of have been
the new hype, you know, since like
solutions like Dumpurify has been where
more implemented a bit everywhere.
Synthesization is now a real standard
in most of the web applications.
Well, yeah.
All the post message tricks,
you know, and the CSPT, the
traversals, been like the new craze.
And so the desktop hunters have quickly
adapted and to learn these techniques.
And I think the wider community
would gain a lot to start working on
those kinds of techniques, but it is
additional work.
Yeah.
And it's also, you can see the shift,
I think, from like more server side
processing, moving to the client side,
JavaScript also, you know, brings
bugs with it and, and all the post
message stuff and the things that
they find, the things that they know
about the client stuff, it's crazy.
All the like cookie, even yesterday
in the newsletter, I shared like two
different articles about sharing about.
And there was like one article
that compared parsing in browsers,
in frameworks, uh, and then it
was already so inconsistent.
And then there was another article from
Portswigger.
I don't remember the name unfortunately,
where you had like a version cookie,
which changes the way cookies are parsed.
So you get another layer of it.
And to be honest, I never think I played
with cookies Uh, like the cookie parsing,
I don't think I've had a bug which
would like require me to mess with this.
Yeah, during a life
hacking event in France.
I had another hunter called Brumance,
who developed his own tool to start
fuzzing, you know, other parts of HTTP
requests that you don't really fuzz into.
And he was fuzzing cookies at that time.
I started to uncover some, like, beginning
of an SQL injection just inside a cookie.
No, that's stuff that you have to test
for, you know, or you just won't do it.
It's just like sometimes, um, I think it's
on petastore lab or something like that.
When you start learning about
SQL injection, you focus on the
parameters and then, well, the
challenge is actually to, well, inject
that into your user agent header.
So of course I never saw it or almost
never saw it in real life in pen testing,
but it still reminds you that once again,
you have coverage that is not being done
properly client side or server side.
There's a lot of things
that we don't test for.
Yeah.
And I also think it's the problem.
You have relatively few bugs you found in
your career because you have like a few
back classes and then a few input sources.
So it's easy to like fall into the
into testing the same same things
all the time because they work.
And then you have a thing like.
SQL injection in the user agent header.
I've never found this,
so I don't test for it.
So in the future, I also won't find it.
So it's sort of the, the negative
feedback loop where you don't find
something, so we don't test it.
So we don't test for it.
And I struggle with like motivating
myself to like fast more things
and test more things that I think.
won't be successful because probably some
of them will be successful at some point.
Another book class, um,
it's very, it's pretty wide.
It's, uh, all the timing
attacks were reported.
So either you go for the James Kettle
route, which is in my opinion, of course,
the way that you will, you know, Uncover
like very, very, very, very impactful
bug, but everything related, you know,
to also timing attack and sandwich
attacks and also time based secrets.
So there is a talk on reset Tolkien where
basically he's shown that even on some
bug bounty targets, he still find like
ideas that are generated, derivated from
a secret that is derivated from time.
And even if we know that he's insecure,
or sometimes you have a gut feeling That
this smells bad and you know that it's
not secure, but you cannot prove it.
It's cool that he and, and all the
researchers have started like building
comprehensive solutions to test
all variations of, for example, is
it like your email plus underscore
plus a timestamp passing to a shower
one or MD five or unique ID and
so on and all of these variations.
And so I think.
Okay.
Like we discussed yesterday, like, um,
having more and more tool kits and more
and more use case being ready to be tested
automatically will greatly help us for all
these time attacks and time based secrets.
Yeah.
There's so many
things to be, to
be found.
Yeah.
And it's a good, good way to think
about it to try to automate this stuff.
So, you know, okay.
I may not believe it will work, but
if it just means pressing a button
and, you know, generating something
automatically, it's less of a hurdle.
If I were to manually inject, let's stick
to the example, SQL injection payload in
the user agent header, in the cookie, in
the parameter, in the body everywhere.
Yeah.
If it's just one button,
then, then it's easier.
So I think it's a good way to think
about it, to try to automate this stuff.
And you know, then it's, if it doesn't
work, doesn't work, not a problem.
The issue is that we end up with the
philosophical question, or are we in the
end, rebuilding some kind of vulnerability
scanner to automate ourselves?
That's the issue that we, we, there's
so many things to be tested and I
got to develop like your instance,
your spider, your spider sense, but.
Well, then you just have to avoid
being stuck into your routine and,
and the issue with bug bounty, and
especially if you do it for money,
uh, is that you need profitability.
And so when you're stuck into that
eternal cycle of, I need to make
money, then you're less likely to
be doing research and then going
outside of your comfort zone.
So you gotta find the right balance.
And that's why, uh,
that's what I strive for.
So is to just have hacking as a
passion that can really research
rather than say, okay, this makes money
and I should keep doing it because.
You know, it supports my,
my lifestyle, my family.
Yeah,
it would be, would be fun to
have this, this way I try to,
this video won't be published, so
maybe I can, I can say about it.
I tried to hack some software that I use.
I tried to make a video.
I had the idea to make the video of like
hacking different software that I used
that does not have a bug bounty program.
It ended up with like me finding a
full read SSRF in 19 minutes, because
I But then I was like, and I plan
to spend the whole week doing this,
but then I just lost the motivation.
It was like a week is too, too a lot.
And then, you know, it's fairly easy to
find bugs and would be, would be cool
to, to feel allowed to just, okay, let's
spend a week hacking on whatever I want.
Well, Yesterday we talked about, you
know, um, the, the way that your brain
process happiness and you know, everything
related to your dopamine levels and the
way we are also kind of victims of that
because now that there is a financial
rewards, we are often bound to, um,
Consider yourself and Oego as hackers
as somehow correlated to the bounty
that you make and also the value of
the bug that you find being correlated
to the amount of money that you make.
Which is not a, which is of course
good in a way because it stimulates
you, you've got that dopamine, that
adrenaline rush and you want to,
you want, you want to go forward.
You cannot stay in that loop forever
because at any time though you
will find less bugs or sometimes
there are underrated value program.
You cannot devalue yourself.
Cause then you just go into a very
bad spiral cycle of self deprecating,
you know, faults.
Yeah.
That's bad.
I do it.
I try to not do it, but still, even
though it's financially, it's easy
to like manage a time with no, with
no bounty mentally, this is the
hard part for me to like, okay.
Cause I, I feel it's more of a sort of
reward that the bounty itself is, of
course it pays the bills, but it's more.
a way to, to, you know, as you
say, to express the, how well
your, your, how good your bag was.
And yeah, it's hard when you have a
worse period, worse bags, downgraded
severity and stuff like this.
And sorry, I'm keep going off
road with you
is this one.
That's something that is
not talked about, I think.
I don't know if I, I think it
affects all the people, but not a
lot is like the blues or the small
depression after a life hacking event.
Yeah.
Like the, the high and the
personal investment of this cool
live hacking events is crazy.
Yeah.
It ends up.
Like at the top, you know, of the climax,
when you read all inside of the, the live
hacking event, you see all the people,
you see money flowing, you see crazy
bugs, you see show and tells, and like,
it's so much excite, excitement that,
and I think when you go back home after,
like everything feels less stimulating.
And I kind of feel like a little
bit depressed for a week after.
Yeah.
Because they're way less stimuli.
I think, okay, well back
to daily life, I guess.
To be fair, I didn't have this.
I was surprised.
I know some people have it.
Yeah.
And I spoke with Johan and he
was like, Oh, how was the life?
I can even argue depressed after.
I'm like, no, I'm pumped up.
I met so many people.
I had so many ideas.
I just want to hug man.
I had like the complete opposite.
And also the.
The life hacking event is
like more stressful because
you want to find the bugs.
You feel the pressure.
After I came back from Edinburgh,
I slept so well because before each
night, if I, if I, if I wake up and
the bounties and updates, and then I
came back and I slept so well for me,
it's like, Oh, so the opposite school,
let's go back to access control box.
So what exactly is this?
What, what is it that you test?
Well, it ranges from the classic idle.
So
add one, decrease by one.
That's a classical one.
But you know, um, depending on the tech
stack and the type of ideas that are used,
you have like various, um, uh, sneaky
ways to get those access control issues.
One thing that I liked, um, uh, I
spent a month in on LinkedIn, that
program made, I think, 30K, something
like that in bounties overall.
Crazy, not that crazy, but still, I
think a good amount to express that
I spent and invested time in that.
And so I was reading the activity
and they have a few disclosed
programs, um, sorry, reports on it.
And LinkedIn use a lot of urns.
So you have, for example, uh, URN,
uh, columns, some, uh, prefix, for
example, user ID colon and some, and
some alpha animal string after it.
And the guy found a, a very
cool, uh, second level bug.
where he filled inside of his profile,
a value being an, uh, a new run.
So it was the key was a URN
and the value was also a URN.
And this value was later sourced by the
application at a different location.
And so it retrieved the value of this.
Like, injected URN and this
process didn't actually, uh,
provide good access controls.
It was able, for example, to access
other people, uh, data through it.
It's like a second order injection
where you put, uh, instead of a
string, like, uh, like, uh, an URN.
That's, for example, in
my opinion, a cool bug.
Yeah.
So it's like second order processing.
And then it's pretty much anything
ranges from either to testing, uh,
authenticate, not authenticated.
And if I'm really, really trying
to go into finding all the little
scrap bugs that I can find, then
it's like, take your time on the, um,
metrics of rights of an application.
Do you have?
Yeah.
Okay.
Five levels for the authentication,
like, are you sure that all of
these five levels on the 200 like
actions are properly implemented?
And I sometimes I do that,
but I find it a bit boring.
Yeah, that was supposed to be my
question because 200 endpoints
times five rows, it's 1000 tries.
That's a lot.
Yeah.
And honestly, there's one guy
that's way better than me at that.
It's Frisek.
He's a French hunter.
And I remember in Edinburgh, I said, Hey,
you should take a look at this application
because it has maybe like 10 levels
of privilege with almost all of that.
So enjoy this crazy guy, like push maybe
16 reports in the next hours, the next
couple of hours, because you know, you
got to feel, you got to get organized
and then you just got to be efficient
and compare it to the documentation.
That honestly tires me too
much to do it properly.
Automate this process in Norway.
No, I know a lot of people use
odd matrix or odd Z and so on.
Yeah.
I can get my head around
to get to, to use them.
Even if they look like
very great solutions.
Most of the time when I use
them, it just to like test
authenticated, not authenticated.
Just to have a quick
replay, but not that much.
And it's also an issue for me because, um,
uh, it doesn't work on complex workflows.
So if you use, for example, a three
step workflow and you want to test
the last step or the workflow.
Uh, if you use something that replace
your cookies, it won't work because
sometimes you need like the correct
ideas for step one, step two, step
three, and then as step four, you
have to modify and get the right idea.
And so investing time in those multi
step workflows will allow you to find the
bugs that other people do not find, but
mostly, well, you cannot automate them
because it just breaks the whole chain.
Yeah.
From, from my tries is like, you
can automate the get endpoints.
Most of the time, but then when it's
posts of, um, update of resources or
deleting resources, it's hard to modify
them because either you will struggle
to determine by the response, if it was
successful or not, because if you're
creating something with a post, you'd.
Don't usually know from the response,
if it was created on your account or
the victim's account deleting, like as
well, it might be problematic because
you cannot directly replay the request.
So I also just do the manual thing.
I think, uh, in the, in the next future,
like even right now, uh, carefully crafted
AI engines could help you for that because
if you really decompose the problem.
Uh, and you have like an AI
agent that does one small thing,
but that does it really well.
You can have like more,
uh, reliable results.
I mean, um, if you first, I don't know,
add a product to your baskets, uh,
then, uh, add the customization option.
Then, you know, try something
else, like put that item into
the basket of another user.
Like having just a very small AI
agent that verifies, okay, uh, is
the answer, uh, plausibly correct?
Yes or no.
Given that input, that input and
that expected output, only does
that real small task might be easier
to apprehend or to understand the
potential vulnerabilities that you have.
And I think that it's a very,
really underlooked the way to craft
really, really small agents to do.
Yeah.
That's a good one.
It's way more powerful.
Like, um, if people want to dive
a bit into that, just take a look
at Daniel's Miestro's Fabric tool.
It has a lot of prompts that are pre
made and really allows you to show, to
understand how to customize those prompts.
And I really like that.
I have small agents that
were perfectly unreliable.
So would you, do you, do you use
an agent like this or do you think
it's, it's possible to create it?
No, I don't use them right now because
I'm working on all the AI projects.
But I think, yeah, it's, it could
be, uh, it could be useful, but I
think that's a couple months of, you
know, fine tuning all this stuff and
it's almost a project of a company
by itself.
Yeah.
But I do see the potential in it.
I think by the time we get like
a full blown hacking agents.
It's going to be a long time because
it's a lot of vulnerability classes, a
lot of things to understand to create
something that, you know, takes the 200
routes and the permission matrix and
goes through the different resources.
Yeah, it's, it, it should be
fairly easy.
The thing is that if you want to
do build that, as I said, you have
to have like very small agents that
do one task and one task perfectly,
then change those very small agents.
And.
Each agents.
So we'll take an input, provide
an output to the next agent.
And so you have this famous chain
of faults between unit agents that
do one thing and then one thing.
Well, then you have to preserve
the context and the context
window is like limited.
So maybe you have two, 200,000 tokens on,
on the cloud, LLM, something like that.
But the more context you provide and
the less pertinent your result will
be, and so your challenge will be to
provide just enough relevant context.
Well, maintain, you know, the
understanding of the application of, and
of what you're doing, but that's possible.
And it's a couple of
months of work, I think.
So we said you, you hacked
on LinkedIn for a little bit.
What is your usual bug bounty program?
Cause I will tell you one thing I noticed
when preparing for the interview in
many of the profiles of top hunters,
like top program is like a private
one that I don't even have access to.
And they have.
often thousands of reputation
in a single program.
Your profile looks different.
You look your profile, there's many
more well paying public programs.
So you're like taking the program with a
lot of competition and you still succeed.
So, so what is your, your usual target?
You
know, it's, it hasn't been a long
time since I got back into full
time back hunting, maybe the end
of March of this year of 2024.
So maybe it makes like
nine months in the year.
And out of those nine months, I think
it might have taken three or four
months just for me, like seeing people
that I never saw before, going to see
family, relatives, taking a bit of
holidays, working on other side projects.
So I wasn't hacking for that much time.
That's why the data set
is a bit more limited.
But, um, yeah, I did a
full month on LinkedIn.
I did a full month on some private
program that had like One 100 K
in the potential reward was like
a infrastructure related bug.
So it prepared, it put be a
bit actually for double us.
Uh, and then, yeah, there was,
um, there was Amazon that I wanted
to look into and have all over us
and no, it's like, you got to get
invited to the double us program.
So I was really happy of getting into
it after the, the LHC and mostly, uh,
I think this is going to be my, my next
program for the foreseeable future.
But, um, you know, when you see
a lot of top hunters in the end.
There's not that much of very big paying
program that do also live hacking events.
So in the end you still have like
those, this small club of maybe, I
don't know, there's Uber, Paypal,
Capital One, Salesforce, AWS, Amazon.
Epic games.
Yeah.
Now, TikTok, you've got a
pretty small subset of programs.
So in the end, well, you're, you're
running around the clock, hunting all
of these programs, but, um, you, you,
you're, you're right off, um, when
you're talking about people specializing
in one program, because most time you
spend there, of course, you know, the
bugs, you know, the steam, you know.
How they handle the things, you know,
how to maximize your output, how to keep
the good relationship with the program.
So, yeah, I think I'm going to stick
with, uh, with AWS, like very large
scope allows you to be very creative.
Both doing like classic web bugs to
more infrastructure related bugs to
like exploring in depth, some features.
And I think it's a great all around
program.
I love it.
Yeah, it's nice.
And the attack serve is
absolutely massive as well.
How about YesWeHack?
Because you also hack there.
There, I do not have as much
visibility into the stats.
How would you sort of compare
hacking on HackerOne and YesWeHack?
It's a bit different
because YesWeHack is a European
platform, French based.
Uh, I've followed them and I've
been friends with them for years
and it's a great company and people
in there are really, really, really
awesome, really great people.
And, um, it's a bit different.
Um, basically when you're in Europe,
you don't necessarily have that
much large companies like in the U.
S.
So, of course, the size of the programs
and the payouts will not be as big
as, uh, as it goes on, uh, on H1.
You can expect from a company that's
not on Amazon to pay a hundred K bucks.
That's just not realistic.
Um, but it's, uh, it's a small platform.
And, uh, from when I was very active
on the platform at that time, I felt
like the 3H quality was higher, you
know, um, I'm less active there.
So I cannot, you know, give factual
feedback on how it is now and nowadays.
But you know, it feels like a bit
more humanizing than, you know,
when you're on big platform that
you feel that sometimes people don't
read your report and, and so on.
So.
I really enjoyed that more, uh,
you know, closer, more human,
more family like, uh, concepts.
Um, the thing is, if you take a look
at the, the bug bounty markets in
the end, like how much areas in the
world where you can sell bug bounty,
Northern America, which is of course
one of the richest countries, South
America, which is emerging, but there
are still not a lot of companies,
Europe that does have money and Europe,
you have mostly these Western parts.
It's like starting to have enough
companies with strong enough,
you know, arms to, to bear
the load of the Black Bounty.
And then you got this EA, so Southeast
Asia, HAC 1 has the, the, the
American market, ESWI HAC is mostly
predominant on the European market
and fights with Integrity on the rest.
And so the next battlefield
is Southeast Asia.
So yes, he's implemented in, in SCA
and now the CEO, uh, Kevin, who's an
awesome guy in SCA, I know, well, I go
on is also starting to get cleanser.
I don't know.
I know less about integrity,
but then it just shows you that.
You know, the quality and the type of
programs and the evolution of the bug
bounty platform will be directly bound
to the clients that are able to get.
Yeah.
And so you've got those
big juicy programs on H1.
You've got those European and start of SEI
program on, on Yes React, and it gives you
overall different targets and different
ways to interact with the programs.
It can be cool, I think, to
change and rotate platforms.
If you feel burned out with working
with certain types of companies,
because the culture is different.
Yeah.
Working with European companies is
different from working with American
based companies or SEA companies.
Like, it's a different way
to interact with people.
Yeah.
Also like, uh, the LHEs, the live
hacking events, how are they different
on ESP Hack to the HackerOne events?
HackerOne events are pretty large scale.
You often get like 100 users
all flown out to some very cool
location like in Vegas or wherever.
Um, Yes React has two types
of live hacking events.
Uh, the first one being a small
punctual event associated to like a
larger event, let's say cybersecurity
conferences or cybersecurity,
you know, general public events.
And they will often hold a small
competition like 24 to 48 hours, uh,
in it a reduced price pool because
often, well, these are just the people
that are going by or people that are
specifically going to the, to the LHC.
So the wallet size is obviously lower.
If you only hack for a day,
you're not going to find as
much bugs as you, as you would.
And then there are some dedicated,
uh, life hacking events that are
bigger, larger scale, uh, which
are, for example, the last one being
in Italy with, uh, no, in France,
in France with the Louis Vuitton.
Uh, luxury, uh, brand.
And so they were flown out to Paris
into like the real headquarters and they
invited way more, uh, hunters, including
North American hunters, uh, as well.
But it's, it's still a smaller scale
where you cannot compare, I think
the, the, the behemoth that is a hack
one to European companies, not yet.
How did you get involved with
the HackerOne lifehacking events?
Uh, in 2022 with the AWC, so
the Ambassador World Cup, I was
with, uh, Maybe for those who
don't know what Ambassador World
Cup is, could you maybe explain?
Yeah, of course.
The Ambassador World
Cup is an annual event.
That started in 2022.
It's a bit like a football or
soccer for your US friends.
It's football.
So it's like a football competition where
you have like, um, teams per country.
Sometimes if there are too
many people, there can be like
multiple teams per country.
Then you've got the selection phase.
Which will eliminate some, uh, some teams.
Then you go into a classical world cup
style of football, where you got like
16 teams and eight fought and two one
until the, well, the final one stands.
And though each country has an
ambassador, uh, that represents, well,
the country with his team and that
is directly in, in, in relationship
with hacker one and with the, with the
programs to coordinate both the hackers.
And the, the relationship
with the platform.
Um, and the rules have evolved a bit.
Nowadays, it's like you've got
a set of programs per round.
So all teams hunt on a specific set of
programs, usually two to three programs.
But 2022 was wild, man.
Very wild.
Like now it's, yeah, yeah, no, it's
like properly set up, you know,
you've got your free programs and
they take time between it's in 2022.
It was so wide.
We were like all the World Cup
teams on all of the managed
public programs of HackerOne.
Do your thing.
And it was around, I think
it took around one month.
And, uh, and, uh, a sad story in the real
world, but a fun, kind of fun, uh, joke
here is that during that time, the war in
Ukraine started getting worse and worse.
So they started banning, for
example, well, because there was
bans, you know, for, for recreation
purpose on some Russian programs.
So for example, the mail.
ru program was present at the time
and disappeared during the cup.
So yeah, it was a bit chaotic, but very,
very, very fun because like people were
submitting All around the platform.
And yeah, that's why, where we, we got
the first World Cup with the French team.
And the, in the end we spent
a lot of time on Epic games.
And so as we specialize a bit more
on that program and we had like very
good hackers, Snorlax, who was very
successful on Epic games to help a lot to.
Really understand the program, find a box.
And, uh, that's how basically we got
the, the first, uh, I think, uh, how
I got the, the, the first invite.
I don't remember if I was a
plus one or if I was invited.
I think I was invited as a, as
a, as a customer sector program.
That was my first, yes,
live hacking events.
Yeah,
I had to take the time to brag
because now the Ambassador World Cup
this year, I'm also playing as, as,
as the ambassador of team Poland.
We are advancing to the final
eight, France loses out.
So it's a payback for, for the
football World Cup, because in the
football World Cup, you eliminated us.
Now we didn't directly
compete, but, uh, yeah.
But you guys
deserve
it.
Very
talented people.
You're
doing an awesome
work
and it's great to, to see you go forward.
So, yeah, we, I didn't expect it as well.
We didn't have so many hunters that
would be so much so, so active.
So now I'm, I'm really proud of the
team 'cause uh, yeah, and, and it's
also not that we just advanced, we
actually scored a lot of points, so.
Awesome man.
Congrats.
Yeah, congrats.
Congrats to the whole team.
How can somebody that, uh, would
like to get involved in the a WC get?
'cause it's only 20 people.
In Poland it's like fewer hundreds,
so it's not as much of a problem.
But in France, I imagine there's.
Hundreds of people that would
like to be part of the team.
So how can one get involved if they don't
have as much reputation on the platform?
The thing is,
um, even it's like a big
event in the bug bounty world.
Um, it's not as much publicized yet.
Yes, it's the first, third year.
So people are getting more and more known
to it and might want to, to get into it.
But the first thing is, uh, also
about fighting imposter syndrome.
So that you don't have to be
okay with, I'm not able to get
into, to get on, to get on board.
Like I know that the French, French
team, one of the French team last
year was comprised of a lot of
young, uh, of young hunters and
they still perform pretty well.
So that's, that's the first
thing being confident.
The second thing is, well, um,
even if there is more and more back
hunters, finally the people that
really wants to get involved, uh, go
fewer and fewer with like the level
of dedication that you put into.
And so once you really start to be
active in those kinds of circles, we
are still kind of Not that numerous.
They're not mad at much people
who really want to go inside
and to go on to the team.
And then as the ambassador is
the one person that is making
the final decision, final call on
who's going and who's not going.
Don't forget that ambassadors
role is also initially to promote
the bounty in their own country.
So you're not just going to take like the
old, Top performing guys all the time.
You have to give the chance
to your rising stars.
And that's why you are in the roster.
You will, I will have some new guys
that are coming in, that coming fresh.
That's a great way, you know,
to have your, like your own time
of glory, if you feel like it.
I would also say to, it's good to
get involved in the community 'cause
it's now it's, it's also as a, as the
ambassador, I also want, I've, I've
heard tips from other ambassadors, you
know, it's good to put somebody in the
team that maybe has a little bit less
experience but is maybe more passionate,
more motivated, active in the community.
So I imagine it's also a
good way to, to get involved.
Yeah.
Consistency.
Just being to able to put in the, the,
the work and also keep in mind that.
This, the World Cup takes almost a
year, you know, and a year is very long.
People sometimes get burnouts,
people have other issues,
have other stuff to deal with.
And so even your top hunters
might, well, at some point
not be available at that time.
And so you've got to have people
on the roster who are able to
take like the fight, keep going.
So, yeah, just, just get those
young guys and girls and,
you know, those rising stars.
It's the moment.
Yeah.
Okay.
Once you already get the LA to invitation,
you perform really well and all the events
you've, you've attended, you get to go
the show and tell you got the top 10.
So what's the key to perform?
Well, The thing is, I think my
only real capability is to, Deep
to dive, but mostly, um, find the
knowledge that I need for something
that I feel is going to be vulnerable.
I'm don't consider
myself as a good hacker.
I suck at a lot of things.
I suck at client side.
That's finally coming from you.
Yeah.
But you know, uh, when I hang out
with other guys, like, I don't know,
maybe the worst guy in the room.
Like, You know, you hang out with
CTF guys who are like complete
brutes on so many topics.
They, yeah, that's true.
Okay, well I suck at everything.
good.
You go with some good clients, guys,
they talking about you, they're talking
about like, stuff you don't understand.
You see the show and tell, say, uh, you,
you asked me as a second slide , but
I, I think I'm only good as much as the
extent of my knowledge and so I have like.
My monkey brain processing a bit
of knowledge, then you have to find
the right information at the right
time to be able to find that bug.
And so even if you, when you start
doing bug bounty a lot and pentesting
a lot, you have your instinct of what
is going to be vulnerable or not.
And that's kind of your
unique approach, but.
Having the gut feeling of something
being vulnerable is not enough.
You gotta transform it just like into
rugby, you know, you place it with
the ball and then you gotta shoot
it and transform it into a point.
And so that's where like being able
to grasp and retrieve information
from different people, different
sources, really makes a difference
on how well that feeling is going to
be or not an actual vulnerability.
And then it's pacing the cursor.
Um, when to stop and when to
keep investigating because bug
bounty is kind of profitability.
So if you invest too much time on a
single bug and it doesn't pays out,
well, finitely you have wasted a lot of
time and you feel bad about yourself.
And then just it's, it's being able to
place like the right course or one where
you should stop or where you should invest
more time or, but we'll simply keep that
in the back for later for another friend
who might be smarter than you, you know?
Yeah.
And.
How they're going at the right time.
So yeah, it's feeling good with the
program and being able to seek the
right information at the right time.
For example, I never did, you know,
AWS infrastructure hacking before.
Yeah.
But you know, right people,
right time, right information.
It's finding that sweet spot,
which makes a difference.
So what were the things you
focused on, on, on the hacking events?
I knew in which event, for example, the
last one, you focused on infrastructure
on AWS, the previous ones.
Did you also get like a one sort of one
goal that you wanted to, or one area?
Oh yeah.
On
Epic games, I focused on a very
classic web app, purely marketplace.
And, uh, I did my usual
thing with access controls.
And the thing is sometimes,
well, people don't care about it.
Because it's not impactful or it's
not impactful in their own security
model and then you gotta accept it.
So after like spending two weeks of doing
everything like
that and getting like, well, yeah, No,
you're gonna get a low hanging, a low bug.
Then you feel doubt.
Damn, I spent really two times
like covering the whole platform
and covering secret features.
Uh, I even spent like 2, 000 on
the premium subscription on it.
It was worth it in the end.
Oh, nice.
But yeah.
And so, yeah, well, I
was quite, uh, confused.
Kind of tired.
And so what I did in the end was to
fall back to something that I really
never tested at scale before was trying
to test denial of service issues.
And that's when I started to
find some, you know, nice bugs.
And paradoxically, the two weeks
of work that I did when to uncover,
you know, hidden attack surface,
accessing premium features, like
even broken features or things that
were not implemented yet, accessing
them and so on and so on, didn't pay.
Much in the end.
And I've made almost all the money in
the end with a couple of those bugs.
How about those bugs?
Aren't they out of scope usually?
Yeah, they, well, they are.
They always are like almost all
policy will have like those bugs.
I think it's, it's
really program dependent.
It's.
Out of good sense, because they
don't want people to spawn a thousand
DPS and start doing some volumetric
doses because it doesn't add any
added value and anyone can do it.
And you know, it just going to bring some
issues for the, for the people in France,
but application level doses or sometimes.
accepted.
And once again, it depends on which
program you're working on and the
security maturity of that program and
which parts of the application you're
able to crash, potentially stop.
Yeah.
And so in the end, there's
still an availability metric.
And this availability
metric is not related to.
Destroying information.
It's literally in the spec making a
system not available, not the data in it.
It's not making the system not available.
So let's say that in a couple of
requests, you're about to crash.
I don't know the shopping cart
of all users in the marketplace.
Yeah.
Hell, that's, that's impactful.
And then you've got to walk
a fine line because you can't
really test that in prod.
Most of the time, either you have a
suspicion, a very hard suspicion and life
hacking events are cool in the way that
you can talk with the final program or
demand validation, that's a good thing.
Or, well, you just scale up properly
and progressively and you just, I don't
know, create enough objects to slow
the server response to three seconds,
five seconds, 10 seconds, 15 seconds.
And you cross check with another
user from another IP with another
account to ensure that you indeed
have a cross user, um, account
impact.
So would you also test DOS on a, let's
say a public program where you don't have
the direct connection of the customer?
How would you, and if you would, how
would you watch out to not cross the line?
With those bugs that
are kind of, you know.
on the fine line that you
felt not really cross.
Um, there are two things.
The first being, um, don't look
like a complete fool to the program.
So if you're starting to, you know,
cross that line, at least make sure
that you've got a really nice impact
and not that you're crushing like some
small things that, No, the program
doesn't really care about make sure
that you've got actual like potential
that you have actual potential impact
on something that is really big because,
you know, if you are going to do
something, do it well, especially if
you're, you know, crossing the line.
Second part is, uh, if you
have like something like.
You send one request and it's
permanently crashed, yeah, don't do it.
But you're going to have a very hard time
with triaging and then the final program.
So it depends on who you are
talking with during the triage
and how the program receives it.
Sometimes it's going to be yes,
sometimes it's going to be a no.
And if it's just a no, well, You
know, you lost your bug, but at
least you didn't have any issue.
But if sometimes it's something
that can be like a bit smoother,
uh, for example, you create a lot of
objects in the database and then you
return all of these objects at once.
At least you control the amount
of data that is returned.
So you can create them progressively
1000, 2000, 3000 and so on and so on.
And just assess the
response time of the server.
And so if some of you start seeing like
response time for five to 10 seconds,
In its case, like linearly with the
amount of object or action that you
perform, then logically, you know that
it's sufficient to make a first report.
And then often it's going to end up
like, yeah, no, that's not enough.
So you ask, okay, should I go further?
Let's say go further.
You do show a significant, uh,
higher delay or sometimes it would
just say, no, it's out of scope.
Yeah.
And then it's quite a weird situation
because they want you to show impact, but
they not allowing you to show impact, but
it's just the role of the game that you
decided to play by trying to use this, uh,
this kind of, uh, our books, but honestly
on more major program is less of an issue.
So would you send the report, let's say
when you have a response of 10 seconds,
or would you look for, for a higher delay?
What is sort of the, the ideal response
time that you would think shows the impact
without actually impacting too much?
It depends also on, um, how it impacts
other users, because sometimes you
can augment, improve the response time
for yourself, but this is going to
be, for example, a very short spike.
At one set point in time, for
example, that's a book a, and so
when another user user site, if it's
at a book, a plus one millisecond,
maybe he will not be impacted.
So The thing is, you gotta cross
check to ensure that it actually
works, and if you cross check with
another user and get a delay of 5,
10, 15 seconds, I think it's enough.
And, um, consider that in a lot of
DOS cases, the proof of concept that
you're going to push is not going
to crash your platform instantly,
but rather provide like a sufficient
delay enough at a fixed point in time.
And it's only if you really
continue way past that point that
you might consider crashing the
platform for a bit longer of time.
So it's often scary, but you often have
like a lot of room, you know, between
having an actual worst case scenario
impacts.
So do you actually, when sending
the report, you also like, Test that
the delay is present for another
user with another IP address,
then the sort of attacker user.
Yeah.
For me, that's the gold standard.
Okay.
And that's what I was often
asked on some programs.
And at least it really shows that if
you have no bias and even as though
it's like less cool to do because
it's actual additional work to have
like kind of a second computer or
second IP and so a second account.
Yeah.
Uh, at least it ensures for yourself.
But by applying this methodology, you
have a real applicable reports and
not just like being almost all of us
hunters being very bound to your own
vulnerability, say, no, I know it's true.
I know it works.
Sometimes it doesn't.
And being a bit strict about that
kind of methodology allows you
at least to be a hundred percent
sure that you have an actual bug.
It still feels good because
even if that's rejected.
You found something
and you feel good about yourself.
Doesn't it feel, because when I think
about it, the sort of problem in my
head is if it's a, let's say there's
a single worker and let's say I have
a second, it causes a 30 second delay.
I know that if the, if I tested
from the another account, It may
get routed to a different worker.
So let's say there are four workers.
I would have to send four 30 second
requests so that this user is affected.
So I would have to sort of brute force
how many workers are there by essentially
sending requests that I would prefer
avoid to avoid sending too many of.
So like, how do you, do you manage this?
In my opinion, there's no good solution.
Um, I was talking with Blacklist
about another bug, the class, so not
another By doing statistical work,
he understood that he's run a bit if
worked like one out of four times.
So once again, possibly different
workers on different code bases,
it just had to, well, repeat
until he got the right worker.
And I think that the same issue, but
once again, it depends on how much
room you have until actually crushing
the, the, the, the, the Walker.
So sadly there's no good solutions
in my opinion.
Yeah.
It's a hard problem.
How much.
If you were to estimate the percentage
of how many of your DOS reports
were accepted, is it like 50%?
Something like this?
More?
Less?
Well, I did most of them
during LHEs, I think.
And so during LHEs, I'd
say 70 percent of them.
And outside LHEs, Well, I, what
I found was way less impactful.
So it was still accepted, but it
was like a, a low or medium bounty.
Okay.
So I think that the context and
the impact makes a difference,
but it's not to be generalized
to all programs.
Yeah.
It's also good to know at the LHE,
you're one of the 100 hunters,
so you're kind of trusted.
Yeah, exactly.
It's also helped if you have
already, if you accepted bugs
that show the team out, this guy.
Exactly.
Yeah.
He doesn't report only DOS bugs,
he also reports good stuff, so.
But if you take DOS on a more general
scale, for example, you know, CP, DOS,
things like that, it's often like pretty
well accepted all around bug bounty
programs, or at least more major ones.
So things should not be too
much of an issue if you have
something that's really impactful.
Yeah.
Coming back to, to the topic
of, of LATs, you've been to,
to free life hacking events.
So how has your approach changed
from the first one when everything
was new to the third one when
you already know what to expect?
I think it grows with your own maturity.
You know, being a bit more
organized, knowing the common
pitfalls, knowing like your own
issue with your own mental problems.
And so it's similar to be, I think,
just a better bug bounty hunter overall.
Like, I don't know, when I was first doing
that Epic Games LHE in 2023, it was It
was cool, but I was a bit more lost, you
know, and yeah, organization thing, I
think makes, uh, makes a good difference.
Like for example, in Edinburgh,
uh, I worked with another
French hacker, Gerusha.
That's where we got the
most impactful team.
Quite a nice award to have.
Yeah.
And, uh, Right at the beginning, like
we created a dedicated discord server
with different channels so that we can
have, you know, stuff sorted out, but
that was not too much into organization.
Like if you have too much
channels or too much, you know,
cases, not going to use it.
It still has to be a little chaotic.
And for example, the other thing I
did on AWS was, um, I spent like, uh,
just maybe one day before the event.
Like a whole day of spending time,
uh, reviewing all of the services.
Like I went to the catalog and
click and read the description of
maybe 30 percent of the services,
because there's a lot of services
and just making small spreadsheets
on saying, Oh yeah, that may be cool.
That may be cool.
That might be cool.
But that's why I think it's cool.
And it lowered me when I have like, when
we endured hardships or, you know, it was
hard not finding bugs, losing motivation
to have like kind of a spreadsheet Hey.
That one, I didn't test it.
And so you can keep your motivation
high by having like fallback scopes
and avoid that the, the eternal
cycle of, I'm not finding bug.
I need to find a new scope.
I'm not finding bug.
I'm stuck finding new scope.
I think it helps a lot with,
um, maintaining morale.
And morale is honestly my, for me,
that, that's the key because if you
or your team is depressed, you're
not going to find any bug, you're
going to maintain your confidence,
you're going to maintain your inertia.
And it's like almost all esports.
If your guys are motivated, if
your guys have high morale, high
confidence, they're going to be
on a roller coaster of, you know.
As soon as moral drops, you think
like, no, this is not worth the time.
This is not worth the effort and you
feel less energetic, less motivated.
And of course you're going to miss
bugs because you're less involved in
doing the actual work to find the bugs.
So yeah, that, that
makes a good difference.
A little bit more of organization
and being able to better maintain
you, you, your mental health
during the, during the events.
How do you.
Manage your focus during the event,
because the mistake I've done was like,
I wanted to focus completely on the LHE
and it was just too much and it ended up
being worse than if I, you know, stuck
to my, to my routine, to my sports.
So how do you manage your,
your time during the LHE?
Well,
I'm going to jump a little bit out of
the box and, um, It all comes down to
how you handle your performance yourself
as entrepreneur, as a backhunter.
Um, back in the days, and that's why
also I think caused health degradation
for me was I was all about the grind.
So.
If I'm something important, I'm
going to wake up early, I'm going
to grind very late and I'm going
to stop until I've done what I've
done for extended periods of time.
That was my first LHE and honestly
I felt it on my health because I
didn't sleep much, I smoked a lot of
cigarettes, drank a lot of caffeine
and it hasn't impacted anybody.
And the grind works.
If you're able to maintain a certain
amount of work, even do your performance
drops, if you're just putting the raw
brute hours, you will make a difference.
That's not something that you should
do in my opinion in the long run.
And then when you gain more maturity,
you understand that is more akin
to a marathon and not a sprint.
So you gotta manage yourself properly.
And so if you manage yourself properly
as an individual, you gotta take
advantage of your peak focus hours.
And you know the saying, like, people
can work being productive at most
five, four, five hours per day.
And then what is the rest?
I don't believe in purely being
productive for four or five hours a day.
I feel the difference.
I think like my top hours or
maybe three hours of full focus.
And that's where most
of the work get done.
But for me, you've got to find
the right balance between the
pure and dumb grind and only, you
know, maximizing your peak focus.
You've got to find the right balance.
And then in between of that, you gotta go.
And enjoy, uh, indeed your rest, your
hobbies, life, your wife, and so on.
And so you, you do see the difference
when you start to find that right balance
because you maintain your moral, you
maintain your routine, you feel good
as an individual, and it just shows
off in your, in the, in the final walk.
Yeah.
For me, the sort of problem that, um,
that I have with this sort of, because
I do believe there's few hours during
the day that can be really productive,
but in the background with you, I feel.
It's as important to have these, you
know, really focused hours to solve a
problem, write a script, come up with a
bypass, but also the hours you're just
at the computer using the app, triggering
different flows, looking for the, the
one point where you can then find,
spend this, this focused time bypassing.
So it's necessary to also
like just spend a lot of time.
You don't really have to be super
focused and, uh, yeah, it's sort of,
you know, you can never plan for it.
And that's sort of why, where, where I
struggle is, you know, just three hours
a day is not enough because you know, if
two and a half hours are just browsing
the app and not actually finding a
particular bug, it's too, too little.
And then, you know, that's, that's where
I find myself having a very various.
Amounts of hours on different days.
That's if you just got to
find the right balance.
Yeah.
And if you get that sweet spot on you're
going to have bugs, you just, you have to
work on all, you know, of your workhorses
to get the actual job done.
That's perfect.
How to not feel that, you know,
Especially in the, in the group of
like 100 hackers with so many top
guys, how to, to still stand out, how
to not feel the imposter syndrome.
Honestly, I still feel terrified.
Like, I know that I'm maybe likely
because of, you know, the rankings,
going to get a next LHC invite.
And I told you about that yesterday.
I'm damn terrified of the next LHC
because I don't feel confident or I don't
feel like, uh, I I'm going to perform
well and I'm afraid of the scope that
is going to be if there is one and I'm
afraid of the, none of the people there
because people are quite friendly, but
I'm afraid of, um, that competition.
So what I do is, uh, forget about that.
The thing is you're, even if you're kind
of competing with other guys and girls,
uh, actually you're just competing with
yourself and you just run your own race.
The thing is, at an LHC, you got
a lot of people working on the
same program right now, but you
only know it because it's an LHC.
Which work on Amazon
or other good program.
Do you see the people hacking in
the same time, the same focus?
No, you don't see them.
No, I don't.
And so what you do is simply, well, put in
the work, stay in your bubble, enjoy the
ride, talk with other people, because it's
cool, it's an emulation, people are having
fun together, finding cool bugs, etc, etc.
But disconnect yourself from the, from
the direct competition, or else You're
going to try to rush some things and get
them badly and poorly done because you
must keep in mind that in LHE you have a
duplicate window which means that during
the two first week of remote hunting,
uh, every bug that is duplicates will be
split between all of the duplicates so
if you are duped you will still get paid.
Which means that if you have like
a super cool bug chain, you don't
care about having your bug stolen
by another one, you can just put
in the work to have a quality.
Time and quality bug chain.
And so when you start forgetting about the
competition and just focusing on having a
nice bug, you will find cool bugs because
you invest two weeks of time and you
will find something that is very nice.
But in the end, isn't that just the advice
that generally applies to bug bounty?
Forget about the other people,
find cool bugs, get the reward.
In the end, that's the secret
that's, in my opinion,
that it's the same thing.
Yeah.
For me, for me, it works.
At the first event, I looked at the
leaderboard and stuff like this.
The second event, you know, I'm
sitting here, you made as a team
200k on AWS, I made like 18.
If, if I just compare myself as
always, he made five times as
much for me, 18 K for three, three
weeks of work, it's still a lot.
So, you know, I'm happy with this
and it's probably the only way to
like keep the, the same mentality.
So yeah, it's, it's really, really
smart to, to, you know, look
at yourself, look at your box.
Also.
Being a duplicate of somebody at
an LHC, it can be kind of an honor.
Oh, I do this guy.
It's cool.
So, so you don't even see it as negative.
I don't get the exact quote, but if I
remember correctly, it's from Miyamoto
Musashi, you know, the book of five
wheels and, uh, and everything he
related to samurai fighting on the
Bushido, the way of the samurai is that
today's victory is to be greater than
the person that you were yesterday.
Yeah.
And tomorrow's victory.
is to be greater than what he
calls the lesser man, which
includes, well, basically yourself.
That's the way that you should see it.
You're walking your own
road and find your own bugs.
In the end, competing with other
people and pushing them, trying
to find the bugs before them, it's
not going to work well for you.
That's what I wrote, you know, I
wrote a small blog article about,
you know, performing in LHE.
And the thing is, thousands of
hackers made Thousand, millions of
dollars per year on those events.
And it works because they are not
fighting with photo, they just have
their own style, own unique approach.
Yeah, that's, that's a really good, and
honestly, the unique approach is not
like I have a super secret nested bug.
No, that's not the case.
It's based sometimes only,
for example, the, the way you
perceive the security model.
You also mentioned collaborating
during the, during the event.
So can you tell us more a bit,
you know, how does it work?
How do you split the bounties?
What sort of, how do you split the tasks?
The
gentlemen agreement for
me is the standard 50 50.
Uh, obviously by bounties,
complex situations can evolve.
People can stop.
Can.
get more or less involved.
And of course, in a lot of cases,
people might feel not comfortable
with, you know, doing the full 50 50.
I'd rather do it even if my teammate
doesn't work, because at least I know
that I will always be full clean.
Get your 50 percent cut.
If you like, we will stick together.
If you don't like, we'll split ways.
It was fun working with you, but at least
that's a gentleman agreement for me.
That's what I did, for example, with
Noxious in, uh, in the, in the, um,
in the Las Vegas, uh, event where
we finally collaborated on some
bugs and say, okay, don't worry.
We are collaborating on
that type of bug class.
So I had a couple of reports before.
I'll put you at 50 50 because I trust you.
I want that to be fully fair.
And that's what we did with Gerusha
again at Enumbr, it was, okay, are
you willing to invest your fully?
Yes.
Are you willing to do a 50 50?
That's the standard agreement.
He told me, okay, I have a, I have
a day job, so maybe sometimes I will
not be as available as yourself.
Is it okay for you?
Yes, I don't care because I trust you.
And then you just find the
right people at the right time.
Gentleman agreements go on and then it's
just trust and being a complimentary
on your skillset helps a lot.
So what do you get out
of the collaboration?
Um, three things, moral and confidence,
because it's always cool to have
an all hacker with you and not just
alone fighting the odds, the Kraken,
the Titans of big bounty, it's cool
to have like a, a teammate, uh,
just to hang out and grow out with.
Don't mind me, don't you care
about you enjoy being around.
That's the first thing.
And as I said, moral is very important.
Uh, second part is indeed when
you have complimentary skill set.
I'm terrible at client side.
Gerusha considers himself bad at
server side, but that's a lie.
And so at least when I had
something that I didn't, I had
no idea about, he helped me.
He, uh, he was doing some very cool
code review, for example, like,
There's so many things where, you know,
people get complimentary, or even when
they have both the same skillset, at
least you have a, you know, different
point of view, different perspective.
And so, you know, uh, you know,
when I arrived here, you, I told you
about a potential bug that I had,
you start talking me away, maybe
you can do that, that, that, that.
Hey, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, slow down.
Cause I just told you about the bug.
I didn't even thought about that.
We were just having a coffee
and I couldn't, couldn't resist.
And that's, that's pretty crazy.
And I think that's still what's impressed
me the most when I talk with other hunters
at LHs or other events is the way that
they perceive the potential attack path
based on the signal potential flow.
Each time I, Oh, I never
thought about that.
And so, yeah, it's a moral.
Where a complementary skill set
and you know, the way to perceive
the potential attack path.
Yeah,
that's nice.
Let's, let's talk about
tools a little bit.
Uh, are you using Burp or Kaido?
I'm a Burp guy, but I
have like a lot of tools.
I have a love hate relationship with them.
Like, Burp is battle tested.
That's why I stick with it.
Know how it behaves.
I know.
It's limitations.
I know that it evolves quite quickly
since the Kaido being more competitive.
I love how they are implementing
cool stuff like BAMDAS, B checks,
and so on, but I also hate the
way they are implementing them.
They have a low heavy
relationship with them.
Kaido is a new cool kid in town.
A lot of top hunters are switching
to Kaido and I feel I understand why.
I don't know for now.
I, uh, when I tested it, like, Months
ago, I felt like it had not yet all
the features that I wanted to have.
But at the same time, it has features that
I wanted to see, like, natively in Burp.
It just bothered me, so.
Burp Suite, extensions, custom extensions.
For now, it does the trick for me.
What extensions?
Top three, I would say, um, So when I
need logging, It's logger to send to
Elasticsearch or log resource, log request
to SQLite, who logs the request to SQLite.
Uh, Piper, Piper is super iterated.
It's crazy.
I have like a ton of
scripts for, for Piper.
To do what?
Everything.
Um, first thing is I want to right
click and be able to save any number
of requests or response to the disk.
Okay.
Clear text.
Not that burp.
Weird format.
I want the full clear text.
I want to be able to extract only
the JSON request or response.
I want to have it beautify.
I want to be able to compare it.
I want to be able, I don't know, to
replace dynamics, dynamically some stuff.
I want to be able, for
example, sometimes to apply.
Like specific GQ features
to some specific stuff.
And so a lot of things just to
process data, to save data, to disk
and, uh, yeah, to sometimes have
like graphical interfaces to, well,
do dynamic divs or, um, I have even
one that calls, uh, JSON crack.
So for example, if I have a very big, uh,
JSON, I send a, um, I do a right click.
Send to JSON crack and then I have
a graphical Explorer to show me the
visualization of the JSON file and
some fuzzy finding to find like the,
the right keys and how it's nested.
Yeah.
I use Piper a little bit.
I think it's underrated.
I think it can do a lot of things.
Although recently, since they introduced
BAMPDAS, I also use some custom columns.
So things I used to do by like Piper
scripts, I now just have a custom column
with the BAMPDA and, uh, I don't know,
extracting GraphQL name of the operation.
For example.
I used to have a, a, um, Piper
script to do it now, it's
just, you know, another column.
So, so it was nice.
What, what,
what about them does it's a very cool
feature, but they just like, and, uh,
I've been in an interview with them to
give them some feedback and they like the,
the way to save, you know, your Banda.
So you can quickly switch, uh,
between, uh, code, you know, snippets.
Yeah.
For search.
For, for columns.
Yeah.
That's pretty cool.
Uh, what was the extension?
You mean?
Yeah.
Uh, I had at one point I used a bit
of CSTQ, I think it's, um, uh, it's
like, uh, an embedded cyber chef.
inside burp and it can also
do like custom manipulations.
For example, all the operations
that you're able to chain in cyber
chef, you can apply them to some,
uh, ingoing or outgoing requests.
And so, you know, when you're a dumb guy
like me, who cannot learn hack Vector, who
didn't take the time to learn hack Vector,
you have at least a graphical way to, you
know, move blocks with your monkey brain.
Decode base 64.
So yeah, I like this one.
Uh, and then yeah, just
mostly additional bandas.
Like for example, I know Ryan Ratter
has, well, it was on his discord.
I think that I saw, you know, something
with the HTTP header, like just to
highlight, for example, the beginning
of a sequence of requests, it's very
cool to have that band that to apply
your specific coloring on the flight.
So you see the beginning of
each sequence when you click
an action, something like that.
And that's pretty much it.
I started using Burp Bounty,
but never really stuck with it.
Uh, and the GS result to have
the, you know, the GS stored
inside Visual Studio Code.
And outside Burp?
Outside Burp?
Um, depends.
When I need to do some
fuzzing, it's a good old Fuff.
Does the trick for me.
Really like it.
Uh, GQ, of course, and the JSON
crack to graphically explore it.
I really like the, the way you can
like quickly explore the stuff.
Let me think because.
I'm using any stuff.
Some extensions like TempleMonkey,
you know, when you need to modify the
DOM quickly to remove some elements
or do some quick actions, like know to
remove the disabled part of something.
That's pretty, that's pretty nice.
Uh, I've got a self hosted
interactor slash server for
out of bounds interactions.
I've got a couple DNS zone for,
um, you know, um, DNS rebinding.
And, uh, and various
variations, uh, around that,
uh, man, I think that's pretty much it.
And of course you got to know some
classic toolkit that you once in a
while you go with, you know, some
SQL map or GW to track, but you
know, it's very specific to an issue.
Variations of DNS rebinding.
Did you mean?
If I'm correct, there's like a three,
four, five different methods, you know,
where the browser goes onto your website
and then you hold it for a couple of
seconds and you change the DNS record.
There's one where you send two
DNS record at the same time.
Uh, and, uh, it's, uh, I think it's Rhino
who made a tool for that, which is DNS.
Rebind multi A, something like that.
Okay.
There are other ways, also some variations
to clear the, to clear the cache by
no saturating the, the, the number
of, of DNS respondents you send them.
So it's, uh, well, like there was five
or six variations, I think, in the tool
singularity when you set up it properly.
And then you got other tools
like DNS rebind multi A and a
couple other ones on GitHub.
Okay.
I didn't know all of them,
so I have to check this.
Yeah.
It's, uh, it's, it's cool to set
up, but it's boring because you
have to set correctly your DNS
zone and all the tools and so on.
And then you can just customize the
JavaScript on the page and the tests.
It's cool.
Yeah.
How about AI?
I know you have some great ideas for
using AI in the future, but today,
how, how does it help your hacking?
That's multiple levels.
Um, I don't know.
I love what, uh, Justin was saying,
uh, regarding, uh, you know, keeping
yourself in a good flow state.
And there's another French hunter called
LaLuca who takes a lot about, who talks
about, about that, about keeping yourself
in a good flow state and avoid having
like breaking interactions and so on.
So I love how, um, When AI is correctly
integrated into your workflow, so you
don't have to open Chrome, go to chat GPT,
create a new chat or something like that.
So I have a lot of bindings, you know,
so just, I can interact quickly with AI.
I have like, uh, self hosted, uh,
LibreChats, which is, uh, you know,
simply in the, um, Using the, the APIs
of the most paper popular LMS providers.
And you can self force it.
So you can like have a graph, nice
graphical interface with all your power
methodized queries, your prompts that
are all correctly stored in one place.
Yeah.
So it's pretty cool.
And uh, it also adds some other features.
For example, big A GI, which is another
application, allows you to do something
called bim, which allows you to query
multiple random providers with the same.
Prompt, so we can compare
the questions that you like.
Uh, and sometimes there is also multi
step rezoning, for example, where you
take two or three LLMs, different LLMs,
working on the same things, and then
makes a diff and unified response.
That's a lot of cool stuff.
Um, I started working on
Daniel Niestereur Fabric.
So it's a CLI tool, which, um,
has like a collection of prompts,
maybe a hundred, 200 prompts.
Very cool.
And so basically you
can pipe anything in it.
So from your command line, you can say,
for example, uh, SQL map, uh, dash dash
help, and then you pipe it into fabric and
specify the prompt that you want to use.
So for example, you provide, well,
your inputs from your terminal into,
well, your AI agent and your prep
and your pref configure prompt, for
example, to ask him to, well, generate
you the perfect SQL map, I don't
know, command at some point in time.
And, um, It's very cool because it
integrates natively, you know, into
your environment, but mostly, um, it
has like very high quality prompts
or, or to organize them and how to
ensure that you get quality results.
So it's pretty nice as well.
Um, I was starting to develop also a
BURP extension, you know, and I recently
saw Justin sharing the, the, um, and
his team, um, the integration that
they made into Kaido, you know, you
do a shift L and you got, uh, that.
And, uh, I was initially developing
something like that for myself.
I got to check if I have the time
and the strength to endure, you know,
coding in Java for that much time.
But yeah, that's the kind of thing
I do.
How do you see the future
of, of AI in hacking?
Is AI going to replace bug bounty?
Not necessarily, but you know,
as all things, um, you know, and
the maturity level of different
Sorry, the technical capabilities of
the attackers also, uh, also improve.
And so not necessarily because for now we
are pretty far from having the real, you
know, artificial general intelligence,
um, and we are still stuck by context.
So context is pretty much everything.
It's a, it's the state machine, you
know, and if you don't have, you're
not able to maintain context for a
long period of time, you're not able
to, you know, Have really meaningful
in depth assessment of something.
And that's why I talk so much about, you
know, those little agents, this chain
of thought and the way to go around the
limitations of not having enough context.
So yeah, maybe one day we'll be replaced
and that's, that's not a bad thing, but
we will find other things to hack on.
AI is a black box.
No one understand really how it works.
Even like you've got machine learning
engineers who walk under the hood, but.
It's a black box for a lot of people.
Once AI has replaced us, we will hack
AI and then we hack other things.
We hack quantum computers, I don't know.
Yeah, that's the good mindset, like,
if the technology changes, we'll adapt.
There's always been need
for security somewhere.
Yeah, we can't be, um, like attached
to a technology or to a specific time.
Like by nature, it's always evolving
technologies or rapidly, you know,
also deprecating like how many
weeks can you wait before there
is a new JavaScript framework?
Two weeks, maybe.
It's bound to evolve.
And, um, hacking is the art of learning,
not necessarily the art of exploiting,
but it's mostly the art of learning
and then applying those skills.
Yeah.
Good.
We'll, we'll come to an end.
Uh, Tell me, what are you looking to
achieve in, in the upcoming year, 2025?
Uh, basically, I'll, I'll try to keep
around because of very cool events.
And of course we make big money with them.
And, uh, I need, I think to, to keep
building some wealth very honestly.
Yeah.
And, uh, I'd like to also, uh, diversify
myself outside of the cybersecurity world.
So for now I have said project with
AI, but I also like, for example,
to have, you know, some real world
businesses to ensure that, you know.
This is, we are living exciting
times, but also very dangerous times.
And I think it's good to have like a
little fit in the, in the real world,
maybe a small restaurant, maybe a
small house, something like that.
You know, you can touch.
Great.
Thank you so much.
It was awesome.
Thanks for listening.
If you want to listen to another
one, I recommend you, uh, this one
in the description and on the screen
right now with Louis from Pentester
Lab, where we talked about getting
into the field, learning about
cybersecurity and, uh, many other things.
For now, thank you so much
for listening and goodbye.